Guide to the Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 3. Personal, Political and Official Files, 1944-2010 TJU.2010.01.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 3. Personal, Political and Official Files
1944-2010
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Specter, Arlen
TJU.2010.01.03
96.67 Linear Feet
The Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 3. Personal, Political and Official Files document aspects of Specter's personal and political involvement during his Senatorial career. Specter served as U.S. Senator from 1981 to 2011, making him the longest-tenured Pennsylvanian senator. The group contains chronological files, memos, schedules, invitations, correspondence, newsclips and publications.
Custodial History
Material was transferred to the care of Philadelphia University in 2010-2011 from the Federal Records Storage Facility in Suitland, Maryland, as well as the Senator's Washington, D.C. and Pennsylvania offices. The physical material was transferred to the University of Pittsburgh in 2014, with the exception of selected photographic and memorabilia items that remain at the Arlen Specter Center's Roxboro House for display. In 2016, Philadelphia University merged with Thomas Jefferson University, and is now known as Thomas Jefferson University- East Falls campus.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Arlen Specter to Philadelphia University in 2010. Philadelphia University and the University of Pittsburgh entered into a partnership to jointly manage the collection in 2013.
Biography
Born in Wichita, Kansas, on February 12, 1930, Arlen Specter came to Pennsylvania to attend the University of Pennsylvania. He married Joan Levy in 1953, and graduated from Yale Law School in 1956. He became assistant district attorney in Philadelphia in 1959. In 1962, Specter was recommended to serve on the Warren Commission, assembled to investigate the assassination of President John F. Kennedy. As part of the Commission, he was responsible for co-authoring the proposal of the "single bullet theory," determining that one bullet struck both President Kennedy and Texas Governor John Connally. Specter ran for Philadelphia district attorney in 1965, switching his Party membership to Republican in order to unseat the incumbent Democrat. He was successful, and served as district attorney from 1966 to 1974.
After an initial failed run for Senator and then for Governor of Pennsylvania, Specter was elected to the U.S. Senate in 1980. He would stay in this position from 1981 to 2011, making him the longest-tenured senator in Pennsylvania's history. During this time, he was a member of a number of Committees: Judiciary (1981-2011; Chair, 2007-2007), Appropriations (1981-2011), Veterans Affairs (1981-2011; Chair, 1997-2001 and 2003-2005), Select Intelligence (1985-1991; 1995-1997; Chair, 1995-1997), Special Aging (1991-1995; 2007-2011), Governmental Affairs (1997-2001; 2003-2005), and Environment and Public Works (2001-2003; 2009-2011).
Though elected as a Republican, Specter was a moderate on many issues, including healthcare reform, immigration, and abortion. He would often cross party lines, such as in voting against the confirmation of President Ronald Reagan's nominee Judge Robert Bork to the Supreme Court in 1987. Specter would again come into the spotlight during a Supreme Court nomination process in 1991, for his cross-examination of Professor Anita Hill regarding her allegations against nominee Clarence Thomas. In 1999, he would vote against the charges brought against President Bill Clinton, giving an answer of "not proven" to reflect his belief that Clinton had not received a fair trial.
As Senator, Specter championed a number of causes and influenced many legislative areas. He was frequently a member of Congressional Delegation trips, particularly to the Middle East, where he would speak out on the cause of freedom from religious persecution and the importance of strong diplomatic relations. He was also a proponent of funding for medical research, including the use of stem cells. He advocated for strict crime laws, particularly for career criminals. His focus on benefitting Pennsylvania could be seen through the pursuit of grant funding opportunities and his attempt to prevent the closure of the Philadelphia Naval Shipyard in the 1990s.
With the worsening of Congressional partisanship in the late 2000s, Specter found himself frequently voting with his Democratic peers. After being one of only three handful of Republicans to vote for the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act in 2009, Specter found himself increasingly marginalized within his party. In April 2009, he returned to the Democratic Party, helping to ensure the passage of the Affordable Care Act. Seeking re-election in 2010, he was defeated in the Democratic primary by Joe Sestak.
Specter's 30-year tenure in the Senate concluded in January 2011. After leaving the Senate, he partnered with Philadelphia University (now Jefferson-East Falls) to establish the Arlen Specter Center for Public Service. In the fall of 2012, Specter, who had previously beaten Hodgkin's lymphoma in 2005 while serving as Chair of the Judiciary Committee, was diagnosed with cancer. He died on October 14, 2012, aged 82.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Arrangement
Group 3 is arranged into six series reflecting aspects of Specter's personal and political involvement during his Senatorial career:
Series I. Chronological Files, 1981-2002
Series II. Invitations, 1981-2007
Series III. Personal Files, 1944-2008
Series IV. Political Party Involvement, 1978-2006
Series V. Schedules, 1981-2010
Series VI. VIP Mail, 1981-2010
Scope and Content Notes
The Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 3. Personal, Political and Official Files comprises 78 boxes of material documenting aspects of Specter's personal and political involvement during his Senatorial career. These files include material documenting his official duties and appearances, correspondence with high-profile individuals, his relationship with the Republican Party at the state and national levels, and personal files related to his background and interests. The group contains chronological files, memos, schedules, invitations, correspondence, newsclips and publications.
Related Material
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 1. Pre-Senatorial Career Files, 1953-1980, TJU.2010.01.01
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 2. Legislative Files, 1965-2011, TJU.2010.01.02
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 4. Office Administration Files, 1962-2010, TJU.2010.01.04
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 5. Constituent Services Files, 1976-2007, TJU.2010.01.05
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 6. Public Relations and Media Files, 1972-2010, TJU.2010.01.06
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 7. Campaign Files, 1976-2004, TJU.2010.01.07
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 8. Awards and Memorabilia, 1957-2010, TJU.2010.01.08
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 9. Photographs, 1930-2010, TJU.2010.01.09
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 10. Electronic Records, 1980-2010, TJU.2010.01.10
Politicians; Invitations; Correspondence; Travel; Personal papers; Republican Party (Pa.); United States. Congress. Senate; United States. Congress; Specter, Arlen
- Chronological Files, 1981-2002; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Chronological Files contains information about Senator Specter's activities, appointments, schedules, and whereabouts on a daily basis. These served as summaries for the Senator and his office staff to keep track of his obligations. Material in this series is arranged chronologically.
  - January 1981 (Box 496, Folder 1)
  - February 1981 (Box 496, Folder 2)
  - March 1981 (Box 496, Folder 3)
  - April 1981 (Box 496, Folder 4)
  - May 1981 (Box 496, Folder 5)
  - June 1981 (Box 496, Folder 6)
  - July 1981 (Box 496, Folder 7)
  - August 1981 (Box 496, Folder 8)
  - September 1981 (Box 496, Folder 9)
  - October 1981 (Box 496, Folder 10)
  - November 1981 (Box 496, Folder 11)
  - December 1981 (Box 496, Folder 12)
  - January 1982 (Box 496, Folder 13)
  - February 1982 (Box 496, Folder 14)
  - March 1982 (Box 496, Folder 15)
  - April 1982 (Box 496, Folder 16)
  - May 1982 (Box 497, Folder 1)
  - June 1982 (Box 497, Folder 2)
  - July 1982 (Box 497, Folder 3)
  - August 1982 (Box 497, Folder 4)
  - February 1983 (Box 497, Folder 5)
  - May 1983 (Box 497, Folder 6)
  - August 1983 (Box 497, Folder 7)
  - November 1983 (Box 497, Folder 8)
  - December 1983 (Box 497, Folder 9)
  - January 1984 (Box 497, Folder 10)
  - February 1984 (Box 497, Folder 11)
  - March 1984 (Box 497, Folder 12)
  - May 1984 (Box 497, Folder 13)
  - June 1984 (Box 497, Folder 14)
  - July 1984 (Box 497, Folder 15)
  - August 1984 (Box 497, Folder 16)
  - October 1984 (Box 497, Folder 17)
  - February 1986 (Box 497, Folder 18)
  - March 1986 (Box 497, Folder 19)
  - April 1986 (Box 497, Folder 20)
  - May 1986 (Box 497, Folder 21)
  - June 1986 (Box 497, Folder 22)
  - July 1986 (Box 497, Folder 23)
  - August 1986 (Box 497, Folder 24)
  - September 1986 (Box 497, Folder 25)
  - October 1986 (Box 497, Folder 26)
  - November 1986 (Box 497, Folder 27)
  - December 1986 (Box 497, Folder 28)
  - January 1987 (Box 498, Folder 1)
  - March 1987 (Box 498, Folder 2)
  - April 1987 (Box 498, Folder 3)
  - May 1987 (Box 498, Folder 4)
  - June 1987 (Box 498, Folder 5)
  - July 1987 (Box 498, Folder 6)
  - August 1987 (Box 498, Folder 7)
  - September 1987 (Box 498, Folder 8)
  - October 1987 (Box 498, Folder 9)
  - November 1987 (Box 498, Folder 10)
  - December 1987 (Box 498, Folder 11)
  - January 1988 (Box 498, Folder 12)
  - February 1988 (Box 498, Folder 13)
  - March 1988 (Box 498, Folder 14)
  - April 1988 (Box 498, Folder 15)
  - May 1988 (Box 498, Folder 16)
  - June 1988 (Box 498, Folder 17)
  - July 1988 (Box 498, Folder 18-19)
  - August 1988 (Box 498, Folder 20-21)
  - September 1988 (Box 498, Folder 22-23)
  - October 1988 (Box 498, Folder 24-25)
  - November 1988 (Box 498, Folder 26-27)
  - December 1988 (Box 499, Folder 1-3)
  - January 1989 (Box 499, Folder 4-6)
  - February 1989 (Box 499, Folder 7-9)
  - March 1989 (Box 499, Folder 10-11)
  - April 1989 (Box 499, Folder 12-13)
  - May 1989 (Box 499, Folder 14-15)
  - June 1989 (Box 499, Folder 16-17)
  - July 1989 (Box 499, Folder 18-19)
  - August 1989 (Box 499, Folder 20-21)
  - September 1989 (Box 499, Folder 22-23)
  - October 1989 (Box 500, Folder 1-2)
  - November 1989 (Box 500, Folder 3-4)
  - December 1989 (Box 500, Folder 5-6)
  - January 1990 (Box 500, Folder 7)
  - February 1990 (Box 500, Folder 8)
  - March 1990 (Box 500, Folder 9)
  - April 1990 (Box 500, Folder 10)
  - May 1990 (Box 500, Folder 11)
  - June 1990 (Box 500, Folder 12)
  - July 1990 (Box 500, Folder 13)
  - August 1990 (Box 500, Folder 14)
  - September 1990 (Box 500, Folder 15)
  - October 1990 (Box 500, Folder 16)
  - November 1990 (Box 500, Folder 17)
  - December 1990 (Box 500, Folder 18)
  - January 1991 (Box 500, Folder 19)
  - February 1991 (Box 500, Folder 20)
  - March 1991 (Box 500, Folder 21)
  - April 1991 (Box 500, Folder 22)
  - May 1991 (Box 500, Folder 23)
  - June 1991 (Box 500, Folder 24)
  - July 1991 (Box 500, Folder 25)
  - August 1991 (Box 500, Folder 26)
  - September 1991 (Box 500, Folder 27)
  - October 1991 (Box 501, Folder 1)
  - November 1991 (Box 501, Folder 2)
  - December 1991 (Box 501, Folder 3)
  - January 1992 (Box 501, Folder 4)
  - February 1992 (Box 501, Folder 5)
  - March 1992 (Box 501, Folder 6)
  - April 1992 (Box 501, Folder 7)
  - May 1992 (Box 501, Folder 8)
  - June 1992 (Box 501, Folder 9)
  - July 1992 (Box 501, Folder 10)
  - August 1992 (Box 501, Folder 11)
  - September 1992 (Box 501, Folder 12)
  - October 1992 (Box 501, Folder 13)
  - November 1992 (Box 501, Folder 14)
  - December 1992 (Box 501, Folder 15)
  - January 1993 (Box 501, Folder 16-17)
  - February 1993 (Box 501, Folder 18)
  - March 1993 (Box 501, Folder 19-20)
  - April 1993 (Box 501, Folder 21)
  - May 1993 (Box 501, Folder 22)
  - June 1993 (Box 501, Folder 23)
  - May 1994 (Box 501, Folder 24)
  - June 1994 (Box 501, Folder 25)
  - July 1994 (Box 501, Folder 26)
  - August 1994 (Box 501, Folder 27)
  - September 1994 (Box 501, Folder 28)
  - October 1994 (Box 501, Folder 29)
  - November 1994 (Box 501, Folder 30)
  - December 1994 (Box 501, Folder 31)
  - January 1995 (Box 502, Folder 1)
  - February 1995 (Box 502, Folder 2)
  - March 1995 (Box 502, Folder 3)
  - April 1995 (Box 502, Folder 4)
  - May 1995 (Box 502, Folder 5)
  - June 1995 (Box 502, Folder 6)
  - July 1995 (Box 502, Folder 7)
  - October 1995 (Box 502, Folder 8)
  - January 1996 (Box 502, Folder 9)
  - February 1996 (Box 502, Folder 10)
  - March 1996 (Box 502, Folder 11)
  - April 1996 (Box 502, Folder 12)
  - May 1996 (Box 502, Folder 13)
  - June 1996 (Box 502, Folder 14)
  - July 1996 (Box 502, Folder 15)
  - August 1996 (Box 502, Folder 16)
  - September 1996 (Box 502, Folder 17)
  - October 1996 (Box 502, Folder 18)
  - November 1996 (Box 502, Folder 19)
  - December 1996 (Box 502, Folder 20)
  - January 1997 (Box 502, Folder 21)
  - February 1997 (Box 502, Folder 22)
  - March 1997 (Box 502, Folder 23)
  - April 1997 (Box 502, Folder 24)
  - May 1997 (Box 502, Folder 25)
  - June 1997 (Box 502, Folder 26)
  - July 1997 (Box 502, Folder 27)
  - August 1997 (Box 502, Folder 28)
  - September 1997 (Box 502, Folder 29)
  - October 1997 (Box 502, Folder 30)
  - November 1997 (Box 502, Folder 31)
  - March 1999 (Box 502, Folder 32-33)
  - April 1999 (Box 502, Folder 34-35)
  - May 1999 (Box 502, Folder 36-37)
  - June 1999 (Box 502, Folder 38-39)
  - July 1999 (Box 503, Folder 1-2)
  - August 1999 (Box 503, Folder 3)
  - September 1999 (Box 503, Folder 4)
  - October 1999 (Box 503, Folder 5)
  - November 1999 (Box 503, Folder 6)
  - December 1999 (Box 503, Folder 7)
  - January 2000 (Box 503, Folder 8)
  - February 2000 (Box 503, Folder 9)
  - March 2000 (Box 503, Folder 10)
  - April 2000 (Box 503, Folder 11)
  - May 2000 (Box 503, Folder 12)
  - June 2000 (Box 503, Folder 13)
  - July 2000 (Box 503, Folder 14)
  - August 2000 (Box 503, Folder 15)
  - September 2000 (Box 503, Folder 16)
  - October 2000 (Box 503, Folder 17)
  - January 2002 (Box 503, Folder 18)
  - February 2002 (Box 503, Folder 19-20)
  - March 2002 (Box 503, Folder 21-22)
  - March 2002 (Box 504, Folder 1)
  - April 2002 (Box 504, Folder 2-4)
  - May 2002 (Box 504, Folder 5-7)
  - June 2002 (Box 504, Folder 8-9)
- Invitations, 1981-2007; II.
  Invitations contains invitations to various events accepted by Specter. This includes political, official, and personal events. Material in this series is arranged chronologically.
  - March 1981 (Box 505, Folder 1-2)
  - April 1981 (Box 505, Folder 3-4)
  - May 1981 (Box 505, Folder 5)
  - June 1981 (Box 505, Folder 6)
  - July 1981 (Box 505, Folder 7)
  - August 1981 (Box 505, Folder 8)
  - November 1981 (Box 505, Folder 9-10)
  - December 1981 (Box 505, Folder 11)
  - January 1982 (Box 505, Folder 12)
  - February 1982 (Box 505, Folder 13-14)
  - March 1982 (Box 505, Folder 15-16)
  - March 1982 (Box 506, Folder 1)
  - April 1982 (Box 506, Folder 2-3)
  - May 1982 (Box 506, Folder 4-5)
  - June 1982 (Box 506, Folder 6-7)
  - July 1982 (Box 506, Folder 8)
  - August 1982 (Box 506, Folder 9)
  - September 1982 (Box 506, Folder 10-11)
  - October 1982 (Box 506, Folder 12)
  - November 1982 (Box 506, Folder 13)
  - December 1982 (Box 506, Folder 14)
  - January 1983 (Box 506, Folder 15)
  - February 1983 (Box 506, Folder 16-17)
  - March 1983 (Box 506, Folder 18)
  - March 1983 (Box 507, Folder 1-2)
  - April 1983 (Box 507, Folder 3-4)
  - May 1983 (Box 507, Folder 5-7)
  - June 1983 (Box 507, Folder 8-9)
  - July 1983 (Box 507, Folder 10)
  - August 1983 (Box 507, Folder 11)
  - September 1983 (Box 507, Folder 12-13)
  - October 1983 (Box 507, Folder 14-15)
  - November 1983 (Box 507, Folder 16)
  - December 1983 (Box 507, Folder 17)
  - January 1985 (Box 508, Folder 1-2)
  - March 1985 (Box 508, Folder 3-6)
  - April 1985 (Box 508, Folder 7-9)
  - March 1986 (Box 508, Folder 10)
  - April 1986 (Box 508, Folder 11)
  - May 1986 (Box 508, Folder 12)
  - June 1986 (Box 508, Folder 13)
  - July 1986 (Box 508, Folder 14)
  - August 1986 (Box 508, Folder 15)
  - September 1986 (Box 508, Folder 16-19)
  - October 1986 (Box 509, Folder 1)
  - November 1986 (Box 509, Folder 2)
  - April 1989 (Box 509, Folder 3)
  - May 1989 (Box 509, Folder 4-5)
  - June 1989 (Box 509, Folder 6-7)
  - July 1989 (Box 509, Folder 8)
  - August 1989 (Box 509, Folder 9)
  - February 2005 (Box 509, Folder 10)
  - March 2005 (Box 509, Folder 11)
  - April 2005 (Box 509, Folder 12)
  - May 2005 (Box 509, Folder 13)
  - June 2005 (Box 509, Folder 14)
  - July 2005 (Box 509, Folder 15)
  - August 2005 (Box 509, Folder 16)
  - September 2005 (Box 509, Folder 17)
  - October 2005 (Box 509, Folder 18)
  - November 2005 (Box 509, Folder 19)
  - December 2005 (Box 509, Folder 20)
  - January 2006 (Box 509, Folder 21)
  - February 2006 (Box 509, Folder 22)
  - March 2006 (Box 509, Folder 23)
  - April 2006 (Box 509, Folder 24)
  - May 2006 (Box 509, Folder 25)
  - June 2006 (Box 509, Folder 26)
  - July 2006 (Box 509, Folder 27)
  - August 2006 (Box 509, Folder 28)
  - September 2006 (Box 509, Folder 29)
  - October 2006 (Box 509, Folder 30-31)
  - November 2006 (Box 509, Folder 32)
  - December 2006 (Box 509, Folder 33)
  - January 2007 (Box 509, Folder 34)
  - February 2007 (Box 509, Folder 35)
  - March 2007 (Box 509, Folder 36)
  - April 2007 (Box 509, Folder 37)
  - June 2007 (Box 509, Folder 38)
- Personal Files, 1944-2008; III.
  Personal Files contains information about Senator Specter's personal activities and interests. This includes information about his career before becoming a member of the Senate that he was often consulted about, including the Kennedy assassination and his time as Philadelphia district attorney. The files also include family and personal correspondence, information on sporting events, and handwritten notes. Material in this series is arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Administrative notes, 1990-1992 (Box 510, Folder 1)
  - Morrie Amitay, 1992-1995 (Box 510, Folder 2)
  - Assassination Records Review Board, 1996 (Box 510, Folder 3)
  - Assassination Records Review Board, 1998 (Box 510, Folder 4)
  - Bible study group, 1985-1988 (Box 510, Folder 5)
  - Bicentennial in Philadelphia, 1987 (Box 510, Folder 6)
  - Herman Bloom, 1990-1992 (Box 510, Folder 7)
  - George Bush, Cabinet and staff, 1989 (Box 510, Folder 8)
  - Capitol Hill Squash Club, 1981-1983 (Box 510, Folder 9)
  - Committee on Ballistic Acoustics Report, 1982 (Box 510, Folder 10)
  - Condolences and well wishes, 1981-1984 (Box 510, Folder 11)
  - Congratulatory correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 510, Folder 12)
  - Congressional Clearinghouse on the Future, 1981-1982 (Box 510, Folder 13)
  - Congressional Records, 1998-1999 (Box 510, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Kissinger Dinner, 1985 (Box 510, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Magic bullet theory and "JFK" movie, 1992 (Box 510, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Mount Airy Dinner, 1985 (Box 510, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Tunisian ambassadors, 1991 (Box 510, Folder 18)
  - Event attendance, 1981-1982 (Box 510, Folder 19)
  - Family correspondence, 1944-1996 (Box 510, Folder 20)
  - Family correspondence, 1970-2000 (Box 510, Folder 21)
  - Family correspondence, 1981 (Box 510, Folder 22)
  - Family correspondence, Franklin Roosevelt Anniversary, 1982 (Box 510, Folder 23)
  - Genealogy and trip to the Soviet Union, 1989 (Box 510, Folder 24)
  - General Motors Discovery abuse, 1992-1996 (Box 510, Folder 25)
  - Handwritten notes, 1991-1994 (Box 510, Folder 26)
  - John Heinz, 1991-1993 (Box 510, Folder 27)
  - Holiday cards, 1995-1996 and undated (Box 510, Folder 28)
  - Hollings/Metzenbaum offensive exchange on the Senate floor, 1981 (Box 510, Folder 29)
  - John F. Kennedy, Assassination records and newsclips, 1978-2993 (Box 510, Folder 30)
  - John F. Kennedy, Inquiries, undated (Box 510, Folder 31)
  - John F. Kennedy, Magic bullet conspiracy, Newsclips, 1991-1992 (Box 510, Folder 32)
  - John F. Kennedy, Magic bullet conspiracy, Newsclips, 1991-1992 (Box 511, Folder 1)
  - John Kyl, 1998-1999 (Box 511, Folder 2)
  - Law students in court, 1992-1993 (Box 511, Folder 3)
  - Letters of introduction, 1987 (Box 511, Folder 4)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1981 (Box 511, Folder 5)
  - Library of Congress, 1989-1992 (Box 511, Folder 6)
  - Mayors of Philadelphia, 1981-1987 (Box 511, Folder 7)
  - Joseph McDade, 1992 (Box 511, Folder 8)
  - Media requests, 1984 (Box 511, Folder 9)
  - Meetings with President Clinton on the Middle East, 1997 (Box 511, Folder 10)
  - Memos to Specter, 1982-1984 (Box 511, Folder 11)
  - Mon Valley, 1981 (Box 511, Folder 12)
  - NBC Einhorn program, 1999 (Box 511, Folder 13)
  - James Nelligan, 1990 (Box 511, Folder 14)
  - Notes, 1996 (Box 511, Folder 15)
  - Notes, 1999 (Box 511, Folder 16)
  - Notes, undated (Box 511, Folder 17-24)
  - Notes, undated (Box 512, Folder 1-8)
  - Notes, Webster, 1986-1987 (Box 512, Folder 9)
  - Northwestern University Law Review, Concluding Address, 1990 (Box 512, Folder 10)
  - John B. O'Hara, 1982 (Box 512, Folder 11)
  - The Octobr Group and Stephen Freind, 1990-1991 (Box 512, Folder 12)
  - Pennsylvania courts, 1993-1994 (Box 512, Folder 13)
  - Personal correspondence, 1981 (Box 512, Folder 14-16)
  - Personal correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 512, Folder 17)
  - Personal correspondence, 1989 (Box 512, Folder 18)
  - Phillies World Series, 1983 (Box 513, Folder 1)
  - Kent Pollock, 1973-1983 (Box 513, Folder 2)
  - Professional correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 513, Folder 3)
  - Professional correspondence, 1981 (Box 513, Folder 4)
  - Professional correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 513, Folder 5)
  - Religious research, 1985-2000 (Box 513, Folder 6-7)
  - Response to "JFK" movie, 1992 (Box 513, Folder 8)
  - Rizzo mayoral election, 1987 (Box 513, Folder 9)
  - Russell High School Reunion, 1987-1993 (Box 513, Folder 10)
  - Schedules, 1984 (Box 513, Folder 11)
  - Senate Financial Public Disclosure Reports, 1980-1982 (Box 513, Folder 12)
  - Arlen Specter, Biographical information packet, 1987-1991 (Box 513, Folder 13)
  - Arlen Specter, Biographies and introductions, undated (Box 513, Folder 14)
  - Arlen Specter, Trivia quiz, 2005 (Box 513, Folder 15)
  - Joan Specter, Elections, 1987-1991 (Box 513, Folder 16)
  - Morton Specter, Anniversary of death, 1995 (Box 513, Folder 17)
  - Shanin Specter, 1992-2005 (Box 513, Folder 18)
  - Stephen Specter, 1983-2004 (Box 513, Folder 19)
  - Super Bowl in Philadelphia, 1984 (Box 513, Folder 20)
  - Temple University Honorary Degree, 1986 (Box 513, Folder 21)
  - Thank-yous, 1981-1982 (Box 513, Folder 22)
  - Thank-yous, 1990-1991 (Box 513, Folder 23)
  - Thank-yous and get-wells, June 1993 (Box 513, Folder 24)
  - Thank-yous and get-wells, July 1993 (Box 513, Folder 25)
  - Thank-yous and get-wells, August 1993 (Box 513, Folder 26)
  - Tree service, 1983-1984 (Box 513, Folder 27)
  - Well wishes after orientation, 1998 (Box 513, Folder 28)
  - Yale Law School, 1987-2008 (Box 513, Folder 29)
  - Youth group meetings, 1981-1982 (Box 513, Folder 30)
- Political Party Involvement, 1978-2006; IV.
  Political Party Involvement contains information about Senator Specter's relationship with the Republican Party. This includes records relating to party platforms, Republican National Conventions, relationships with state and local committees, and correspondence with party officials. Material in this series is arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - 1984 Baron Report ratings (Box 514, Folder 1)
  - 1988 Republican Convention delegate list (Box 514, Folder 2-3)
  - 1998 position questionnaires, 1997-2004 (Box 514, Folder 4)